The applications of reinforcement learning are numerous and diverse.
强化学习的应用领域非常广泛
Ranging from self-driving cars to board games.
从无人驾驶汽车到棋类游戏 无所不包
For instance, one of the major breakthroughs in
例如 在上世纪 90 年代
machine learning in the 90s was TD-Gammon.
机器学习的一大突破性发展是 TD-Gammon
An algorithm that used RL to play Backgammon
这种算法利用 RL
on par with the best Backgammon players at the time.
与当时的顶级双陆棋选手进行比赛
This algorithm advanced the theory of Backgammon
该算法发现了之前未知的策略
by discovering strategies that were previously unknown.
并推动了双陆棋的理论发展
You know, Backgammon is a pretty complicated game.
双陆棋是一种非常复杂的游戏
In fact, it has over 10 to the 20th possible game states.
实际上 它有 10 到 20 个潜在游戏状态
So it's pretty amazing that it was possible to
因此能够教会人工智能体
teach an artificially intelligent agent how to play.
玩这款游戏真的很令人震惊
More recently, progress was made on a game that is much more complicated.
最近 另一款更加复杂的游戏取得了瞩目的进展
Maybe you've heard of AlphaGo.
或许你听过 AlphaGo
An AI agent trained to beat professional Go players.
AlphaGo 是一个人工智能体 专门接受训练打败最厉害的专业围棋手
It's said that there are more configurations in
据说围棋的走法
the game than there are atoms in the universe.
比宇宙中的原子数量还要多
RL is also used to play video games such as Atari Breakout.
RL 还可以用来玩视频游戏 例如 Atari Breakout
The AI agent is given no prior knowledge of what a ball is or what the controls do.
人工智能体事先并不知道什么是球 或者控件的作用是什么
It only sees the screen and its score.
它只看到了屏幕和得分
Then through interacting with the game,
通过玩这款游戏
with testing out the various controls,
并测试各种不同的控件操作
it's able to devise a strategy to maximize its score.
它能够发现获得最高得分的策略
RL was also used to create a bot to beat
RL 还用于创建一个与在线战斗视频游戏 Dota 中的
top players in the online battle arena video game Dota.
顶级玩家进行决斗的机器人
If you are an e-sports fan,
如果你是电子竞技粉丝
you're encouraged to check it out.
建议你了解这方面的信息
Jumping to a completely different domain,
再说说另一个完全不同的领域
RL is also used in robotics.
RL 还用于机器人
For instance, it's been used to teach robots to walk.
例如 我们使用 RL 指导机器人如何行走
The idea is that we can give the robot time to test out
原理是让机器人有一段学习时间
its new legs to see what works and what doesn't work for staying upright.
测试新的腿部 看看哪些动作可以站直 哪些不行
Then we can create an algorithm to help it learn from that gained experience,
然后创建一个算法 帮助机器人从这种经验中学习规律
so it's able to walk like a pro.
这样就能够像人类一样行走
But why teach a robot to walk when you can teach it to drive?
既然能教机器人行走 为何不教它驾驶呢
RL is used successfully in self-driving cars, ships, and airplanes.
RL 成功应用到了无人驾驶汽车 船舶和飞行器中
It's even been used in finance, biology,
甚至用在了财经 生物学
telecommunication, and inventory management among other things.
电信和库存管理等领域
If any of these applications catch your interest,
如果你对任何一种应用感兴趣
check out the links below.
请参阅下方链接